Finding Aid for Melvin R. Gilmore (1868-1940) Papers 1905-1938 and undated
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Melvin R. Gilmore papers 1905-1938, undated
Gilmore, Melvin R. (Melvin Randolph), 1868-1940.
4.25 linear feet
Melvin Randolph Gilmore was one of the preeminent ethnobotanists of his generation and served as Curator of Ethnology for the Museum of Anthropology at the University of Michigan from 1929 to 1939. The Gilmore Papers contain correspondence, topical files, field notes, photographs, and manuscripts related to his work among Native American groups of the Plains and Prairies, including the Arikara and the Omaha.
0384 Aa 2
Sponsor: This finding aid is a product of a project supported by a grant awarded to the Bentley Historical Library and University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology in 2002 by the Division of Preservation and Access of the National Endowment for the Humanities, an independent federal agency.
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The papers (donor no. 9273 ) were transferred by the Museum of Anthropology in 2003.
The records are open without restriction.
Melvin Randolph Gilmore was born on March 11, 1868 in Valley, Nebraska. Gilmore's father was a farmer, and as a young man, Gilmore worked the farm with him. He also served as a teacher in a local school, not finishing college until he was in his thirties. He received a bachelor's degree from Cotner College (later Cotner University) in 1904. He received both of his graduate degrees in botany from the University of Nebraska, a master's degree in 1909 and a doctorate in 1914.
Gilmore served as a professor of botany and zoology at Cotner University from 1904 to 1911. He then became curator at the Nebraska State Historical Society from 1911 to 1916. From 1916 to 1923 Gilmore served as curator of the museum at the State Historical Society of North Dakota. He served on the staff of the Heye Foundation's Museum of the American Indian from 1923 to 1928. After most of the staff at the museum were abruptly let go due to financial difficulties in 1928, Gilmore moved to Michigan and worked as a landscape designer for the Kellogg Nature Preserve in Battle Creek. Gilmore was then hired as the first Curator of Ethnology for the Museum of Anthropology at the University of Michigan in 1929. He was later given the additional title of Director of the Ethnobotanical Laboratory in 1938.
Gilmore was one of the preeminent ethnobotanists of his generation. He was one of the first researchers to recognize the enormous botanical knowledge of Native Americans and to take it as his primary area of study. Much of Gilmore's ethnographic and ethnobotanical field work was done working among the Arikara (also known as the Sahnish), an agricultural Native American tribe based around the upper Missouri River. Gilmore also researched and spent time with a number of other Native American groups on the Prairies and Plains, including the Pawnee and the Omaha. Gilmore's most well-known publication was Uses of Plants by the Indians of the Missouri River Region, first published by the Bureau of American Ethnology in 1919 and considered a classic of the field. Other major publications included Prairie Smoke (Columbia University Press, 1929), a collection of Native American myths, and the pamphlet Indian Lore and Indian Gardens (Slingerland-Comstock Co., 1930).
Gilmore's most significant accomplishment at Michigan was the establishment of the Ethnobotanical Laboratory, which began operation in 1930. Founded with support from the National Research Council, the laboratory served as a national center for the identification of archaeological vegetal material. Unfortunately, Gilmore was in poor health for much of his tenure at the university, and was not able to get very far with the work of the lab. By the mid-1930s he had ceded most of his museum and lab responsibilities to his assistant, Volney Jones, though he retained his museum titles until 1939.
Gilmore died on July 25, 1940 in Lincoln, Nebraska.
Related Resources
Additional Gilmore manuscript materials may be found in the Melvin Randolph Gilmore Papers, Nebraska State Historical Society, and Curator's Correspondence, State Historical Society of North Dakota. The Volney H. Jones Papers, available at the Bentley Library, also include Gilmore materials.
A examination of Gilmore's life and work formed the basis for Melvin Randolph Gilmore, Incipient Cultural Ecologist: A Biographic Analysis by David L. Erickson, unpublished M.A. Thesis, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, 1971.
For further information about the Ethnobotanical Laboratory, see "The Ethnobotanical Laboratory at the University of Michigan" by Gilmore, published as University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology Occasional Contributions, no. 1, as well as the Volney H. Jones Papers.
The Melvin R. Gilmore Papers consist of three series: Correspondence; Research, Writing, and Field Work; and Photographs. With the exception of the Correspondence series, much of the material in the papers is undated, but appears to date mainly from 1905 to 1930.
Subjects:
Gilmore, Melvin R. (Melvin Randolph), 1868-1940.; University of Michigan. Ethnobotanical Laboratory.; University of Michigan. Museum of Anthropology.; Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation.; Anthropology.; Ethnobotany.; Arikara Indians.; Omaha Indians.; Pawnee Indians.; Indians of North America--Folklore.; Indians of North America--Ethnobotany.; Indians of North America--Food.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Gilmore, Melvin R. (Melvin Randolph), 1868-1940.; Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation.; St. Francis Mission (Saint Francis, S.D.); Anthropology.; Ethnographic photographs.; Ethnobotany.; Arikara Indians.; Omaha Indians.; Indians of North America.; Plants--North America.; Corn.; Fishing.; Farming.; Basket making.
Genre/Form:
Field notes.; Photographs.
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series, 1908-1938 (0.75 linear feet), contains incoming and outgoing professional correspondence. The series includes letters written and received during Gilmore's tenures with Cotner University, the Nebraska State Historical Society, the State Historical Society of North Dakota, the Heye Foundation's Museum of the American Indian, and the University of Michigan. The series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, with a folder of miscellaneous correspondence at the end of each letter range.
  Gilmore's correspondence consists mainly of discussions with amateur and professional ethnobotanists and anthropologists about their research, field work, and laboratory results. Gilmore was particularly interested in Native American groups, so a good deal of his correspondence relates to ethnographic and ethnobotanical studies of various facets of the lives of different Native American populations. Correspondents of note include A.B. Stout, J.J. Thornber, George F. Will, John R. Swanton, and Francis La Flesche. Gilmore's correspondence with Fay-Cooper Cole includes discussions of preparations for an ethnographic exhibit for the 1933 World's Fair in Chicago (additional information on this project can be found in the Research, Writing and Field Work series). Aaron McG. Beede's letters to Gilmore include ethnographic notes from the former's missionary work among the Native American groups of North Dakota. A small amount of correspondence related to specific areas of Gilmore's research can be found in the individual manuscript and topical files of the Research, Writing and Field Work series.
  - Alexander, Hartley Burr 1929 (Box 1)
  - American Museum of Natural History 1924 (Box 1)
  - Amsden, Charles 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - A-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Bailey, L.H. 1929-1933 (Box 1)
  - Barrett, Samuel A. 1924 (Box 1)
  - Bartlett, Harley H. 1929 (Box 1)
  - Beckwith, Martha Warren 1929-1932 (Box 1)
  - Beede, Aaron McG. 1916-1924 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Earl H. 1932-1934 (Box 1)
  - Benedict, Ruth 1930 (Box 1)
  - Bessey, Charles E. 1908 (Box 1)
  - Blankinship, J.W. 1915 (Box 1)
  - Brannon, Peter A. 1925 (Box 1)
  - Brigham, Edward M. 1929 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Charles E. 1916-1935 (Box 1)
  - Buechel, Eugene 1925-1926 (Box 1)
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs 1908 (Box 1)
  - B-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Cockerell, T.D.A. 1929 (Box 1)
  - Cole, Fay-Cooper 1929-1932 (Box 1)
  - Cooper, John M. 1931-1933 (Box 1)
  - Coville, Frederick V. 1909-1929 (Box 1)
  - Cummings, Byron 1931 (Box 1)
  - C-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Densmore, Frances 1932 (Box 1)
  - Dixon, Roland B. 1932 (Box 1)
  - D-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Fernald, M.L. 1917 (Box 1)
  - Fewkes, Jesse Walter 1919-1923 (Box 1)
  - Fox, George R. 1914-1932 (Box 1)
  - Freeman, George F. and Forbes, R.H. 1914-1916 (Box 1)
  - F-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Goddard, Pliny Earl 1923 (Box 1)
  - Greenman, Emerson F., ?-1933 (Box 1)
  - Grinnell, George B. 1918-1922 (Box 1)
  - Guthe, Carl E. 1929 (Box 1)
  - G-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Harrington, M.R. 1925-1937 (Box 1)
  - Harshberger, John W. 1915 (Box 1)
  - Henbest, Wayne 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - Hinsdale, Wilbert B. 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - Hodge, F.W. 1915-1932 (Box 1)
  - Hyde, George E. 1913-1916 (Box 1)
  - H-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Jenks, Albert E. 1916-1931 (Box 1)
  - Jenness, Diamond 1931 (Box 1)
  - Judd, Neil M. 1932 (Box 1)
  - J-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Kelly, Arthur R. 1931 (Box 1)
  - Kidder, Alfred V. 1926-1931 (Box 1)
  - K-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - La Flesche, Francis 1913-1926 (Box 1)
  - Lesser, Alexander 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - Linton, Ralph 1924 (Box 1)
  - Lowie, Robert H. 1926-1931 (Box 1)
  - L-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Martin, Paul S. 1933 (Box 1)
  - McGee, W.J. 1908 (Box 1)
  - McKern, W.C. 1932 (Box 1)
  - Menninger, Karl 1932 (Box 1)
  - Mexico 1927-1938 (Box 1)
  - Mooney, James 1913-1918 (Box 1)
  - Murie, James R. 1913 (Box 1)
  - Museum of the American Indian 1924 (Box 1)
  - M-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - National Park Service 1931 (Box 1)
  - National Research Council 1932 (Box 1)
  - Nusbaum, Jesse L. 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Orchard, W.C. 1926-1932 (Box 1)
  - Over, W.H. 1928 (Box 1)
  - O-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Parker, Arthur C. 1915-1930 (Box 1)
  - Pearce, J.E. 1933-1937 (Box 1)
  - P-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Reagan, A.B. 1926-1927 (Box 1)
  - Reid, Russell 1926-1931 (Box 1)
    (includes photos)
  - Renaud, E.B. 1932 (Box 1)
  - R-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Safford, W.E. 1918-1925 (Box 1)
  - Shantz, H.L. 1929-1931 (Box 1)
  - Shetrone, H.C. 1928-1932 (Box 1)
  - Speck, F.G. 1927-1931 (Box 1)
  - Stirling, Matthew W. 1930 (Box 1)
  - Stout, A.B. 1914-1924 (Box 1)
  - Strong, W. Duncan 1931-1938 (Box 1)
  - Swanton, John R. 1918-1931 (Box 1)
  - S-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Tantaquidgeon, Gladys 1932 (Box 1)
  - Thornber, J.J. 1915 (Box 1)
  - Tozzer, Alfred M. 1930 (Box 1)
  - T-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - United States Department of Agriculture 1908-1937 (Box 1)
  - U.S.S.R. 1930-1934 (Box 1)
  - V-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Waugh, F.W. 1914 (Box 1)
  - Wedel, Waldo R. 1931 (Box 1)
  - West, George A. 1932 (Box 1)
  - White, Oland E. 1921-1926 (Box 1)
  - Will, George F. 1914-1936 (Box 1)
  - Wilson, Gilbert 1914-1922 (Box 1)
  - Wilson, M.L. 1914-1915 (Box 1)
  - Wissler, Clark 1920-1924 (Box 1)
  - Wright, Dana 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - W-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Y-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Z-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Research, Writing and Field Work circa 1912-1930
  The Research, Writing and Field Work series, ca. 1912-1930 (2.5 linear feet), is comprised of Gilmore's ethnographic and ethnobotanical field notes, bibliographic research and writing. The series is divided into three subseries, Topical Files, Individual Manuscripts, and Field Notebooks and Loose Notes. (Because Gilmore maintained several parallel filing systems, there is some duplication of content across the subseries.) Most of the material is undated, but appears to have been created and compiled mainly while Gilmore was working at the State Historical Society of North Dakota and the Museum of the American Indian (1916 to 1923 and 1923 to 1928, respectively). Smaller amounts of earlier and later material are also included.
  - Topical Files
    The Topical Files subseries includes field notes, bibliographic research, and manuscripts related to particular areas of study. Some files also include related correspondence. Of particular note are Gilmore's files on the Arikara, Omaha, and Pawnee, which are rich in primary and secondary source materials. A small amount of more administrative material can also be found in the subseries, including a file related to Gilmore's work for the Heye Foundation with correspondence from Gilmore to George Heye regarding field work and purchases for the Museum of the American Indian, and notes for reports on Gilmore's activities at the University of Michigan.
    - Arikara
      - Ceremonialism, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Intertribal Commerce (Box 1)
      - "NonGilmorian" (Box 1)
      - Origin Myths (Box 1)
      - Uses of Plants (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous Ethnographic Notes (Box 1)
    - Bibliographic Research Notes (Box 1)
    - Botany-General (Box 2)
    - Bushotter Texts, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Chicago World's Fair, 1933-Exhibit Planting Plan (Box 2)
    - Clippings 1915-1935 (Box 2)
    - Dakota and Plains Environment (Box 2)
    - Dakota Information (Box 2)
    - Drawings-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Ethnobotanical Gardens (Box 2)
    - Fibers (Box 2)
    - Games of Indian Children (Box 2)
    - Heye Foundation 1923-1925 (Box 2)
    - Indian Botany-General (Box 2)
    - Iroquois Myths (Box 2)
    - John Harvey Kellogg Nature Preserve (Battle Creek, Michigan) (Box 2)
    - Logan Fontanelle 1917 (Box 2)
    - Maps (Box 2)
    - Medicine Bundles 1926 (Box 2)
    - Mother Corn (Box 2)
    - Mother Corn and Her Children Course 1929 (Box 2)
    - Native Life (Bulletin of the Society of Friends of Our Native Wild Life-includes Gilmore articles and editorials), 1921-1922 (Box 2)
    - Nature Lore School 1928 (Box 2)
    - North Dakota Geography (Box 2)
    - Offering Sticks or Waunyanpi 1914 (Box 2)
    - Omaha
      - Food Preparations (Box 2)
      - "Material", 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Osage Preparations of Corn (Box 2)
    - Pawnee
      - General (including Henry E. Roberts) (Box 2)
      - Ethnographic Notes (Box 2)
      - Stories (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 2)
    - Plains-Child Training and Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Pottawattami Vocabulary (Box 2)
    - Reprints (of Gilmore articles) 1915-1923 (Box 2)
    - Southern Cheyenne Geographic Names (Box 2)
    - University of Michigan 1930 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Individual Manuscripts
    The Individual Manuscripts subseries includes drafts and supporting research for various articles and publications by Gilmore and others. Most are brief accounts by Gilmore of various Native American practices and myths, many of which were published in Gilmore's monograph Prairie Smoke and in the Heye Foundation's Indian Notes serial. A few longer manuscripts may also be found in the subseries, most notably Gilmore's reference copy of Uses of Plants by the Indians of the Missouri River Region. The subseries also includes several manuscripts by authors other than Gilmore. Oliver La Mere's "Origin of the Great Mystery Lodge of the Winnebago" includes correspondence from the author to Gilmore, while Elizabeth McCollum's "A Collection of Local Materials Suitable for Use in Teaching Indian Life in Peru, Nebraska" includes Gilmore's handwritten corrections. "Western Sioux Cosmology" was written by Aaron McG. Beede, the North Dakota missionary and amateur ethnologist with whom Gilmore had a strong professional partnership.
    - "A Collection of Local Materials Suitable for Use in Teaching Indian Life in Peru, Nebraska" (by Elizabeth McCollum with Gilmore's handwritten corrections) circa 1933 (Box 2)
    - "A Living Outdoor Museum," 1920 (Box 2)
    - "A Mandan Monument to a National Hero" (Box 3)
    - "A Native American Dinner," circa 1920 (Box 3)
    - "A Proposed Extension of the Work of the Plant Industry" (Box 3)
    - "A Proposition to Make a Survey of the Plant Lore and Geographic Lore of the Indian Tribes of Nebraska" (Box 3)
    - "A Talk Given at the Meeting of the Society for the Propagation of Indian Welfare in New York State," 1927 (Box 3)
    - "A Thanksgiving Day Address of the Seneca Tribe of the Iroquois Indians" (Box 3)
    - "A Tuscarora Corn Legend" (Box 3)
    - "Aboriginal Economic Life in America" (Box 3)
    - "Account of a Victory Dance of Teton-Dakota at Ft. Yates, Standing Rock Reservation, North Dakota, November 30, 1918" (Box 3)
    - "American Indian Engineering" (Box 3)
    - "An American Plant Emigrant to Europe" (Box 3)
    - "An Omaha Ghost Story" (Box 3)
    - "An Omaha Love Story" (Box 3)
    - "Brief Notes on the Vegetation of the Weeping Water Valley with Abridged Lists of Species" (Box 3)
    - "Chahinkapa," 1921 (Box 3)
    - "Children and the Meadowlark" (Box 3)
    - "Current False Notions Regarding American Indians" (Box 3)
    - "The Dakota Ceremony of Hunka" (Box 3)
    - "Dawn Songs" (Box 3)
    - "Description of Butchering of Large Mammals, Such as Buffalo, as Practiced by Omaha in Old Times," 1926 (Box 3)
    - "Description of the Tipi" (Box 3)
    - "Extracts from Testimony in Regard to Various Claims of the Dakota Nation" (Box 3)
    - "Folk Lore Tales of the American Indian" (Box 3)
    - "Geology from a Car Window on Northern Pacific Railway Fargo to Montana-North Dakota Boundary" (Box 3)
    - "History of Ogala Sioux" (Box 3)
    - "How It Came About That Geese Go Away to the South in Winter Time" (Box 3)
    - "How the Usefulness of Wild Rice Was Discovered-A Chippewa Myth" (Box 3)
    - "Immigration of Bird Species," 1921 (Box 3)
    - "Indian Buffalo Hunts," 1912 (Box 3)
    - "Indian Names of Mammals of North Dakota" (Box 3)
    - "Indian Nations of the Prairie Region" (Box 3)
    - "Indians and Conservation of Native Life," 1927 (Box 3)
    - "Interview with Ta-Shunka-Hinanpa," 1920 (Box 3)
    - "Landmarks" (North Dakota) (Box 3)
    - "Life in North Dakota a Hundred Years Ago" (Box 3)
    - "Marshal Foch at Bismarck, North Dakota" (Box 3)
    - "Nature and Health" (Box 3)
    - "Notes on Tribal Geography of the Dakotas," 1912 (Box 3)
    - "Omaha Story of Finding of the Maize" (Box 3)
    - "Omaha Use of the Meat of the Smaller Animals" (Box 3)
    - "Origin of the Great Mystery Lodge of the Winnebago" (by Oliver La Mere) 1926 (Box 3)
    - "Pahok Memorial Association" (Box 3)
    - "Pottawattami Indians Near Athens, Michigan," 1926 (Box 3)
    - Prairie Smoke-Preface (Box 3)
    - "Prehistoric Farmers of the Ozark Mountains" (Box 3)
    - "Remarks on Indian Day at Inwood Park," May 8, 1926 (Box 3)
    - Review of The Fighting Norths and Pawnee Scouts by Robert Bruce, 1932 (Box 3)
    - "Sacred Trees" (Box 3)
    - "Seneca Legend of Man's Acquisition of Corn" (Box 3)
    - "Some Considerations on the Content of Memoirs of the American Anthropological Association, Volume II, Part 4, Being an Account of an Hidatsa Shrine and the Beliefs Respecting It" (Box 3)
    - "Some Cosmogonic Ideas of the Dakota" (Box 3)
    - "Some Foods and Methods of Their Preparation Among the Omaha Indians Previous to Their Europeanization" (Box 3)
    - "Some Notes on the Old Time Methods of Upbringing and Education of a Boy in the Dakota Nation" (Box 3)
    - "State Historical Parks of North Dakota" (Box 3)
    - "Story of the Baby and the Upland Plover" (Box 3)
    - "Sugar-Making Among Indians" (Box 3)
    - "Teokanha's Sacred Bundle" (Box 3)
    - "The American Ethnobotanical Garden of the Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation," circa 1925 (Box 3)
    - "The Bad Dog-A Dakota Fable" (Box 3)
    - "The Bean Mouse" (Box 3)
    - "The Captive Bird-An Omaha Child Story" (Box 3)
    - "The Ceremony of Transmitting the Stick Bundle of the Arikara Book of Genesis and the Doctrine Pertaining to It" (Box 3)
    - "The Chickadee" (Box 3)
    - "The Chipmunk and the Bear-A Seneca Story Explaining the Markings Seen Upon the Chipmunk" (Box 3)
    - "The Coyote and the Gray Fox-A Ponka Story" (Box 3)
    - "The Dakota Ceremony of Letting Go of the Ghost" (Box 3)
    - "The Dakota Song to the Spider-Wort" (Box 3)
    - "The Earth-Lodge" (Box 3)
    - "The Legend of Pahuk" (Box 3)
    - "The Legend of Standing Rock" (Box 3)
    - "The Name of Sakakawea" (Box 3)
    - "The Pristine Prairie" (Box 3)
    - "The Scalp Dance" (Box 3)
    - "The Skunk and the Bear-A Mandan Story" (Box 3)
    - "The Song of the Old Wolf" (Box 3)
    - "The Song of the Pasque Flower" (Box 3)
    - "The Song of the Wren-A Pawnee Story" (Box 3)
    - "The Sorrows of the Corn, and Bean, and Squash People (A Seneca Myth)" (Box 3)
    - "The Story of the Lost Moccasin" (Box 3)
    - "The War Eagle and the Jack-Rabbit-A Mandan Story" (Box 3)
    - "The Wonderful Basket" (Box 3)
    - "Two Good American Games for Girls" (Box 3)
    - Uses of Plants by the Indians of the Missouri River Region, [1919] (reference set) (Box 3)
    - "Western Sioux Cosmology and Letting Go of the Ghost" (by A. McG. Beede) 1919 (Box 3)
    - "When and How Fire Came to Be Used" (Box 3)
    - "Why the Rabbit's Back Has a Singed Appearance" (Box 3)
    - "Why the Winters Are No Longer So Severe As Formerly" (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Field Notebooks and Loose Notes
    The Field Notebooks and Loose Notes subseries is comprised of seven field notebooks, a folder of loose field notebook pages, and seven folders of index cards and looseleaf notes. The folders of loose notes include bibliographic references, information on professional contacts, and Gilmore's notes from secondary sources, as well as his notes from the field. The notes range from typed pages similar to what can be found in the Topical Files subseries to scraps of index cards and loose paper with Gilmore's handwriting. The materials found in both the notebooks and the loose notes form the basis for many of the manuscripts found in the Topical Files and Individual Manuscripts subseries.
    The field notebooks document Gilmore's work with the Arikara and other Native American groups. The largest dates from 1917 to 1926 and includes Gilmore's interview and observational notes from work with Native American groups in North and South Dakota. A smaller notebook dates from 1926 to 1932 and is labeled "Onondaga," but appears to continue the Dakotas field work from the previous notebook. A third notebook is from 1923 and includes notes on the Arikara and Omaha, as well as lists of materials to be purchased for the Museum of the American Indian. One small field notebook contains notes Gilmore made about Michigan. Several smaller field notebooks also contain information on these topics.
    - Field Notebook Related to Michigan Ethnobotany 1929 (Box 3)
    - Loose Field Notebook Leaves (Box 3)
    - Loose Notes, 7 folders (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Small Field Notebooks (Box 3)
    - Field notebooks, 4 volumes (Box 4)
- Photographs circa 1905-1930